

Serhat Sezer

E-mail: serhat.szr@gmail.com Website: http://serhatsezer.wordpress.com

Phone: (+90)5534192000 Address: Site mahallesi, Evren

Sokağı

Ümraniye, İstanbul /

TURKEY

Cover Letter

I am a self-taught software developer who stays calm under stress also communicate effectively with project managers and creative teams. I want to work with mobile projects especially iOS platform. I've three year experience with Cocoa Touch platform. Everyday I'm searching new learning things about iOS development and also contribute other github frameworks for better improve myself.

Objective

To search for a position that will allow me to improve my current software engeering, communication and teamwork skills. From this position, I also seek the opportunity to learn new skills for future use.

Work experience

February 2017 — Present

Mobile Engineer

Brickly.io

Brickly is a software development company based on San Fransisco and Istanbul. I work as a Mobile Engineer. Mainly I developing mobile applications with both Android(Java) and iOS(Swift and Objective-C) also rarely working with React Native.

Kariyer.net

September 2015 — September 2016

iOS Developer

Kariyer.net is a leading company in HR field and it has 100k+ active daily users. I am responsible for developing and refactoring, performance testing, scaling existing apps of Kariyer.net (iş ara) and Kariyer.net (iş veren) apps.

İş Ara App:

https://itunes.apple.com/tr/app/kariyer.net-is-ara/id574794931?mt=8

İş Veren App :

https://itunes.apple.com/tr/app/kariyer.net-isveren/id964176919?mt=8

Freelance

November 2014 — September 2016

iOS Developer

Zebramo marketplace application

Zebramo is a start-up company. I'm developing and designing iOS application. My current responsibilites are leading development process and testing, releasing app to app store. Also I'm teaching my teammates Objective-C and iOS life cycle.

Serbat Sezer

- · Cocoapods for dependecy management
- OOP, Design Patterns (Singleton, KVO, Abstract factory, Category)
- UI Debugging (FLEX Inspector, Reveal)

https://itunes.apple.com/tr/app/zebramo-guvenle-al-p-sat-s/id803287185?l=tr&mt=8

Hotel Same Night

Daily booking hotel application. My main role is developing application from scratch and distributing.

I used some of basic design pattern approaches and other programming paradigm like;

Factory Pattern

OOP

KVO Pattern

Functional Reactive Programming

https://itunes.apple.com/tr/app/hotel-same-night/id1031848747?mt=8

Snake Game

Working with SpriteKit framework and integrated with Apple Game Center.

- Cocoapods for dependency management
- · Game play design
- OOP
- UI Debugging (FLEX Inspector)

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/snake-the-old-retro-classic/id988470127

SecretCV.com

June 2014 — November 2014

iOS Developer

SecretCV is a HR company. My role was to develop and maintenance iOS applications. Using latest technologies and I was lead to other team mates about designing and developing iOS application.

SecretCV iOS application

(This application is a human resource application users find their job)

- Using cocoapods for dependency management,
- OOP and some design patterns "singleton, KVO, Abstract factory)

https://itunes.apple.com/tr/app/secretcv-is-ilanlar/id951011688?mt=8

Tribal Worldwide Istanbul

September 2013 — June 2014

iOS Developer & Interactive Developer

Tribal Worldwide Istanbul is a digital agency. My role was to develop interactive web & mobile web applications using Action Script 3.0 & Javascript - CSS3, JQuery. Also I've developed a native iOS application. In addition to that developed cross platform game using Unity3D and ported this game both iOS and Android devices. During my work process I've worked with project managers and designers.

Süt peşinde iOS game

(Like temple run game)

(Unity3D for c#, Blender for 3D models)

https://itunes.apple.com/tr/app/sut-pesinde/id821578443?mt=8

Kumandan iOS application

Serhat Sezer

(This app only works valentine's day, application basically doing "kind" commands for both lover.)

https://itunes.apple.com/tr/app/kumandan/id665130940?mt=8

Rafineri

August 2012 — September 2013

iOS Developer & Interactive Developer

Mainly I've developed short term interactive projects (Kioks applications, Mobile campaing applications and games) During working with Rafineri I started developing native iOS applications and guide them other team mates about designing and developing iOS applications.

Eti Karam iOS application

https://www.behance.net/gallery/8578455/Eti-Karam-Bir-Karamlk-Yolculuk-iPad-Application

Skills

Personal skills;

- Experience with building complex mobile application
- · Advanced troubleshooting and problem solving
- Good knowledge of UX based on Apple Design Human Guideline

Development skills;

- Object Oriented Programming, Design Patters, MVC, MVVM
- Functional Reactive Programming (RxSwift, ReactiveCocoa)
- UI & Code Debugging Skills
- Test Driven Development
- Working with Web Services and Restful API (RestKit for iOS Development)
- iOS Development using Objective-C, Swift
- HTML5, CSS, Javascript knowladge
- · Android Development knowladge

Education

Uluslararası İlişkiler

September 2012 — Drop out

Anadolu University

This is a distance education program.

English education

September 2011 — April 2011

Galatasaray Univeristy

Interests

- Drumming
- Piano
- Movies
- Travel
- Books
- Swimming

Serhat Sezer 3

References

1. Aytekin Meral (Mobile Developer, London UK) aytekmeral@gmail.com

Serhat Sezer